Guide to the William R. and Louise Fielder Sheet Music Collection
Department of Special Collections
- Series 6. California
  - Subseries f. 20th Century
    - At San Francisco's fair: song San Antonio: P. L. Eubank,1915 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      Words by D. C. McGinnis
      Lithographer: J. B. Payne, Texas
    - California march San Francisco: John P. Broder,1900 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      Composed by Mary Tilden Stairley
      Original, uncirculated sheet music
    - Songs of the gold miners: a golden collection of songs as sung by and about the forty-niners New York: Carl Fischer,1932 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      Composed by Sterling Sherwin and Louis Katzman
      Going to the mines --A California Ball --Clementine --Crossing the Plains --The days of ÔForty-nine --The dirty miner --The fools of Forty-nine --A gambler's life --Gold hunting --Hangtown girls --The honest miner --Leave you miners, leave --The miner's dream --The miner's lament --Oh, what a miner --Poker Jim --Sailing for San Francisco --Sailing Ôround the horn --Sweet Betsey from Pike --We'll strike it.
    - Welcome song 1915 Napa: Florence E. Thomson,1913 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      Words and Music by Florence E. Thomson
    - Columbia, the gem of the ocean San Francisco: Supplement to the Sunday Examiner,1898 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      Written and composed by David T. Shaw
    - Life's game of see-waw San Francisco: Supplement to the Sunday Examiner,1898 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      Music by L. C. Wedgefuth
      Words by Edgar Selden
    - Aloha soldier boy San Francisco: Daniels & Wilson Music Publishers,1918 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Dinky little cable car San Francisco: Stern Music Co.,1951 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      Words and Music by Stephen McNeil and Billy Chinn
    - California Sweetheart: waltz ballad with ukulele arrangement Los Angeles: W. A. Quincke & Co.,1932 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      Words and Music by Dan H. Reese and Kathleen Steele
    - The Yankee hustler march: a tribute to American progress San Francisco: Sam Davis,1902 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      Music by Eugene E. Schmitz, Mayor of San Francisco
      Lithographer: C. W. Nevin & Co.
    - Rose room fox trot San Francisco: Sherman, Clay & Co.,1917 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      Music by Art Hickman
    - San Francisco blues San Francisco: Sherman, Clay & Co.,1916 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      Music by Chris Smith
    - Moonlight at the cliff: reverie Los Angeles: S. Seiler,1901 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      Music by S. Seiler
    - A memory: song London: Arthur H. Stockwell, Ltd.,1932 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      Music by Emmet Pendleton
      Words by Ina Donna Coolbrith
    - 49 San Francisco: Elite Music Co.,[1925] (Box 15, Folder 9)
      Music by Leila France
      Words by Joaquin Miller
    - Meet me at the San Francisco fair San Francisco: San Francisco Publishers,1914 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      Words and Music by Don J. Gono
      Engraver University Engraving Co., Oakland
    - Aloha oe (Farewell to thee) San Francisco: Henry Grobe,n.d. (Box 15, Folder 9)
      Music by H. M. Queen Liliuokalani
    - When the little ones are coming home from school San Francisco: Supplement to the Examiner,1896 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      Music by Charles Graham
      Words by Howard Graham
    - In dear old Georgia San Francisco: Elsie G. Rafael,1904 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      Words and Music by Elsie G. Rafael
      Performed by Bertha Herrera
    - San Francisco, the world's fair town (The city by the golden gate): world's fair song, 1915 San Francisco: Benj. Curtaz & Sons,1915 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      Music by Eddie Jewell
      Words by Andy Graves
    - Chimes of Mission Dolores: reverie with voice obligato Oakland: S. Seiler,1904 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - San Francisco, our beloved, arise! arise! San Francisco: Chartier and Greven,1906 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      Words and Music by Joesph Greven
    - On the highway to loveland San Francisco: Nat Goldstein Music Publishing Co.,1914 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      Music by Nat Goldstein
      Words by M. J. Gunsky
      Performed by Norton & Lee
    - Up-side down: the comic aviation success San Francisco: Southern's Stagecraft Studio,1911 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      Music by A. C. Southern
      Words by E. T. Southern
    - As you were! San Francisco: Sherman, Clay & Co.,1919 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      Music by Leo Flanders
      Words by Max Dill and Harry Williams
    - Those golden bridges Oakland: Harvey & Kernes,1937 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      Words and Music by Sue Harvey and Fred Kernes
    - The island of cuddle and squeeze San Francisco: Nat Goldstein Music Publishing Co.,1914 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - America's first San Francisco: Toobridge Music Publishers,1941 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      Words and melody by Reb. Raney
      Arranged by Harry Powell
    - Wha Wha, that imaginary isle San Francisco: Wesley Webster,1921 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      Music by Lester Stevens
      Words by Phil Furman
    - Mississippi moon: waltz and ballad San Francisco: Nat Goldstein Music Publishing Co.,1922 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Back in San Francisco town s.l.: s.d.,n.d. (Box 16, Folder 2)
      Music by Paul Princelau
    - Song of the wanderer (where shall I go?) San Francisco: Villa Morét Music Publishers,1926 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      Words and Music by Neil Morét
    - Where the soft sweet breath of ocean sweeps our golden western shore San Francisco: George A. Smith,1912 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      Music by Samuel H. Speck
      Words by Herbert Thomson
    - The land of my prairie dreams s.l.: Kiutus Tecumseh,1926 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      Words and Music by Kiutus Tecumseh
    - The soldier's love San Francisco: Lucy Long,1903 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      Music by Alfred A. Batkin
      Words by Lucy Long
    - Up in the air San Francisco: Sherman, Clay & Co.,1918 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      Music by Arthur M. Fournier
      Book and lyrics by Michael Corper and Waldo C. Twitchell
    - ÔNeath the purple lilacs bloom San Jose: Northup Piano House,1903 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      Words and Music by Ethel F. Symonds
    - California here I come: with ukulele accompaniment New York: M. Witmark & Sons,1923 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      Music by Al Jolson, Bud De Sylva and Joseph Meyer
      Performed by Al Jolson
      From :Bombo
    - On to Berlin Los Angeles: J. C. Crisler,1918 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      Music by Lee Johnson
      Book and lyrics by J. C. Crisler
    - I'm strong for camp curry: song Los Angeles: W. A. Quincke & Co.,1914 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      Words and Music by Walter DeLeon
    - You'll be sadder but wiser, Mr. Kaiser, when Uncle Sam gets over there San Jose: McKiernan Publishing Co.,1918 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      Music by Joe McKiernan
    - Emperor Francis Joseg: two-step s.l.: The Sunday Call,n.d. (Box 16, Folder 4)
      Music by Eduard Strauss
    - Souvenir de Los Angeles: waltz Los Angeles: Fitzgerald Piano and Music Co.,1901 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      Music by Paul de Longpré
    - Souvenir waltz Oakland: S. Seiler,1901 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - We'll make California dry!: California Dry Federation official campaign song Los Angeles: California Dry Federation,1914 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      Music by S. Maxwell
      Words by Rev. R. A. M. Browne
    - Yosemite march: two-step New York: Broder and Schlam,1896.San Francisco: Broder and Schlam ,1896 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      Music by George W. Heitzel
    - The dawn of a perfect day Los Angeles: R. W. Heffelfinger,1918 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      Words and Music by Eloise A. McClure
    - The squire's serenade: waltz song San Francisco: Supplement to the San Francisco Examiner,1898 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      Music by Dr. C. B. Root
      Words by Ralph W. Bliven
    - Pacific waves waltzes Angels Camp, CA: J. C. Dorser,1900 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      Music by J. C. Dorser
    - Beautiful valley of Pajaro San Jose: Melvin, Hillis & Black,n.d. (Box 16, Folder 6)
      Words and Music by Milton L. Lawrence
    - California for mine: the greatest song since Ô49 New York: Armstrong Music Co.,1908 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      Music by Edward Armstrong
      Words by Will H. Armstrong
      Printer Falconer & Loveland Print, Los Angeles
    - In the swing: song San Francisco: The Metropolitan Co.,1893 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      Music by Sigismund Blaumann
    - Islam: march and two step San Francisco: Islam Temple,1911 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      Composed by Noble George W. Bennett
    - He jess dawn it, he just done it!: a fictitious waltz San Francisco: L. Budd Rosenberg Publishing House,1887 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      Music by Theo H. Northrup
    - California and you New York: Kalmar & Puck Music Co.,1914 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      Music by Harry Puck
      Words by Edgar Leslie
      Performed by Margarite Stark
    - The Pasadena rose song Laguna Beach, CA: Annette A. Riddell,1929 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      Music by Annette A. Riddell
      Lyric by Isaac J. Frazee
    - I love you, California s.l.: F. B. Silverwood,1913 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - School day sweethearts San Francisco: Sherman, Clay & Co.,1923 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      Words and Music by Glen Edwards
    - Coast defense march San Francisco: Sherman, Clay & Co.,1905 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      Music by Leon M. Lang
    - Remember boys your duty when you're on the firing line: song San Francisco: Ernest Philpot,1917 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      Words and Music by Charles Bridge
    - By the side of the road San Francisco: Weeks & Winge Music Publishers,1925 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      Music by Harold Weeks
      Poetry by Sam Walter Foss
    - Uncle Sam is a grand old man: a spirited war song Santa Barbara: John Christian,1917 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      Words and Music by John Christian
      Arranged by George Clerbois
    - March dedicated to the Sunset excurisons: two-step Washington: Clarence W. Murphy,1900 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      Music by Clarence W. Murphy
    - Lady of leisure: waltzes San Francisco: Albert J. Markgraf,1904 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Smiling moon: three step San Francisco: Albert J. Markgraf,1915 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Home again! from France and Flanders: march song Oakland: Kness Publishing Co.,1919 (Box 16, Folder 9)
      Words and Music by Leo Kness
    - St. Philip's march San Francisco: St. Philip's School,1948 (Box 16, Folder 9)
      Music by Bernie Salin
      Words by A Sister of Charity, B.V.M.
    - The stricken city San Francisco: Examiner,1906 (Box 16, Folder 9)
      Music by Prof. F. Fanciulli
      Words by Ella Wheller Wilcox
    - The American Marseillaise Oakland: Felix Schreiber,1918 (Box 16, Folder 9)
      Music by Felix Schreiber
    - Lady of leisure: waltzes San Francisco: Albert J. Markgraf,1904 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Uncle Sam march song San Francisco: The Hawthorne Music Co.,1909 (Box 16, Folder 10)
      Music by Nick Brown
      Words by George H. madin
    - Aloha oe San Francisco: Les Lorden Music Co.,1914 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - The Irish lullaby, or, the Tra la lee song and chorus San Francisco: George W. Hagans,1891 (Box 16, Folder 10)
      Composed by P. J. Cahill
      Arranged by George E. Ebert
    - The military schottische San Francisco: L. Budd Rosenberg Music Publishing House,1889 (Box 16, Folder 10)
      Music by A. G. Send
      From :Favorite dance music
    - Grand mazourka de concert in D minor San Francisco: Bancroft, Knight & Co.,1878 (Box 16, Folder 11)
      Composed by Leopold Lichtenberg
      Arranged by Isidor Rosencrantz
    - Comrades: a beautiful new song San Francisco: The Maze,n.d. (Box 16, Folder 11)
      Composed by Felix McGlennon
    - On the beach at Waikiki, or, the golden hula Honolulu: Bergstrom Music Co., Ltd.,1915 (Box 16, Folder 11)
      Music by Henry Kailimai
      Words by G. H. Stover
    - On the beach at Waikiki, or, the golden hula Honolulu: Bergstrom Music Co., Ltd.,1915 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Mah' pun'kin Sue: a serenade Los Angeles: Knight Publishing Co.,1911 (Box 16, Folder 11)
      Music by Dolly Knight
      Words by Mabel Rains
    - You are so beautiful: song San Francisco: Sherman, Clay & Co.,1917 (Box 16, Folder 12)
      Music by Lawrence Zenda
      Poetry by George Sterling
    - Songs San Francisco: Sherman, Clay & Co.,1917 (Box 16, Folder 12)
      Before Dawn --Mediatrix --Holy river of sleep --Nightfall --A star --The voice of the dove --The mist and the far off star --Just to be near --Yearning --Violin cello obligato to mediatrix
    - Throop Institute march Los Angeles: Exton Music Co.,1900 (Box 16, Folder 12)
      Music by E. C. Kammermeyer
      Throop Institute is the former name of The California Institute of Technology (Caltech).
    - Just one San Francisco Oakland: Ludlow-Macdonald Music Co.,1907 (Box 16, Folder 12)
      Music by M. Ruth Macdonald
      Words by Lillian H. Shuey
    - Masonic march two-step (On to San Francisco -- Panama-Pacific Exposition 1915) San Francisco: Scholz & Webster,1912 (Box 16, Folder 12)
      Composed by W. B. Ash
    - Way down in Turlock where the watermelons grow Turlock, CA: Turlock Board of Trade,[1904] (Box 16, Folder 12)
      Music by Miss Jean Nelson
      Words by Henry Shadle
- Series 7. California and Hawaii
  - Subseries a. 1850 - 1859
    - Atwill & Cos., fancy goods emporium San Francisco: Atwill,n.d. (Box 17, Folder 1)
      Lithographer: Sarony & Major, Lith., New York
      Lithograph only. No music.
    - I dream of home: ballad San Francisco: Julia H. Backus,1859 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      Composed by P. R. Nichols
      Lithographer: L. Nagel, San Francisco
      Performed by Julia H. Backus
    - El eco del Pacifico: four waltzes San Francisco: Atwill & Co.,1853 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      Composed and Arranged by Jaques Coo
      Yerba Buena --Mission Dolores --Presidio --Golden Gate
    - Unnumbered kisses San Francisco: Samuel Colville,1857 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      Performed by Miss Mary Provost
      Cover only. No music.
    - Cheer boys, cheer Boston: G. P. Reed & Co.,[1853 -1856] (Box 17, Folder 1)
      Words by Charles Mackay, Esq.
    - The lonely watcher: ballad San Francisco: Gray & Herwig,[1860].Sacramento: R. Dale & Co. ,[1860] (Box 17, Folder 2)
      Music by George Croal
      Words by Charles Jefferys
      Lithographer: Drouaillet, Litho., San Francisco
      Also published by A. Waldteufel, San Jose.
    - Go seek me there: song San Francisco: A. Kohler,[1860].Sacramento: R. Dale & Co. ,[1860] (Box 17, Folder 2)
      Also published by Loewy Bros., F. Biestat, San Jose; G. Amy, Marysville; and Kierski Bros. and Rosenbaum & Van Allen, Stockton.
    - Cabrielle waltz: easy and brilliant [two copies] n.l.: L. T. Planel,1856 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      Composed by L. T. Planel
    - Sunset ballad for one or two voices Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1854.London: Oliver Ditson & Co. ,1854 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      Music by Stephen Massett
      Performed by Madame Anna Bishop
      Also published by C. H. Ditson & Co., New York; Lyon & Healy, Chicago; John C. Haynes & Co., Boston; and J. E. Ditson & Co., Philadelphia.
    - The celebrated Highland polka San Francisco: Atwill,[1856] (Box 17, Folder 3)
      Arranged by C. Schultz
      Taught by J. W. Fuller and Sister
    - When the swallows homeward fly San Francisco: Rasche & Sons,[1859 -1860] (Box 17, Folder 3)
      From :24 beautiful songs for hte voice with piano forte accompaniment
      Instrument :Piano Forte
    - O love awake: serenade San Francisco: Salvator Rosa,1853 [1863] (Box 17, Folder 3)
      Arranged by F. H. H. Oldfield
      Lithographer: George F. Swain; George H. Baker, Lith.
    - Cuckoo polka (The appraoch of spring) San Francisco: Salvator Rosa,1851 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      Composed by A. Herzog
      Arranged by Charles Schultz
      Performed by Germania Philharmonic Society
    - Thy daughters, Columbia, are fairest: romanza San Francisco: A. Kohler,1857 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      Composed and Written by Clement White
      Performed by Mr. C. Henry
    - Jennie is my darling: song and chorus San Francisco: A. Kohler,1858.Marysville: D. Bonham ,1858 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      Composed by P. R. Nicholls
      Words by Captain Duncan F. McDonald
      Also published by G. Amy, Marysville; R. Dale, Sacramento City; Kierski Bros., Rosenbaum & Van Allen, Stockton; and Loewy Bros. and F. Biesstat, San Jose.
    - The little white clematis: song San Francisco: Rasche & Sons,1859.San Jose: A. Waldteufel ,1859 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      Composed by Palomita
      Poetry by Owen Meredith
    - The celebrated Nightingale polka San Francisco: Atwill & Co.,1856 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      Composed by Bosquet
      Arranged by C. Koppitz
      Performed by Messrs. C. Koppitz and Carnaud
    - Dear Effie farewell: song San Francisco: Dan H. Douglass,1855.Sacramento: Dougliss & Dale ,1855 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      Arranged by W. McKorkell
      Words by James R. Lawrie
      From :'The Gipsy's Warning'
      Also published by William Hall & Son, New York.
    - Florence Fay: ballad San Francisco: A. Kohler,1859.Sacramento: R. Dale ,1859 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      Performed by Miss Carrie Hiffert
      Also published by Loewy Bros., San Jose; L. C. Van Allen, Kierski Bros., Stockton; G. Amy, Marysville; E. G. Randall, Portland.
    - Mary of Argyle: a beautiful Scotch song San Francisco: Rasche & Sons,[1858] (Box 17, Folder 5)
      Composed by S. Nelson
      Written by Charles Jeffries
    - To home farewell San Francisco: Charles F. Robbins,[1850s] (Box 17, Folder 5)
      Composed by A. Baumbach
      Poetry by W. E. Richardson
    - Home! Sweet home: air anglais varié pour le piano New York: G. Schirmer,1857 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      Music by S. Thalberg
    - The little girl schottisch San Francisco: Atwill & Co.,1856 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Assembly schottisch San Francisco: Atwill & Co.,1854 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      Music by Charles Kohler
      Lithographer: J. C. Pearson, New York
    - The true lancers' quadrille as danced at the state balls (La dorset) San Francisco: Atwill & Co.,[1850s] (Box 17, Folder 6)
      Arranged by P. T. Wallenhou
    - Cuckoo polka; or, The approach of Spring San Francisco: Salvator Rosa,1857 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      Composed and Arranged by A. Herzog and Charles Schultz
    - Ernani: quadrille San Francisco: Salvator Rosa,1857.San Francisco: Atwill ,1857 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      Music by L. T. Planel
      From :Verdi's Opera
      Also published by A. Kohler, San Francisco.
    - The May Queen polka for one voice, chorus, or piano s.l.: L. T. Planel,1858 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - San Francisco thrill schottische San Francisco: A. Kohler,1859.Nevada: J. E. Hamlin ,1859 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      Composed by Frank Stoepel
      Also published by Loewy Bros., San Jose; L. C. Van Allen and Kierski Bros., Stockton; G. Amy, Marysville; and E. G. Randall, Portland.
    - Far aloft our eagles soar: a new national song San Francisco: P. R. Nicholls,1856 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      Words by James Linen, Esq.
    - The San Francisco schottisch Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1858.Boston: Russell & Richardson ,1858 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      Composed by Sep. Winner
      Also published by D. P. Faulds and Tripp & Cragg, Louisville; Geo. Willig, Hy. McCaffrey, and Miller & Beacham, Baltimore; Lee & Walker and Sep. Winner, Philadelphia; Firth, Pond & Co. and William Hall & Son, New York; Wm. C. Peters & Son, Cincinnati; and Salvator Rosa, San Francisco.
    - Ernani: quadrille San Francisco: Salvator Rosa,1857.San Francisco: A. Kohler ,1857 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - ÔTis always sad to part San Francisco: A. Kohler,1859.Sacramento: R. Dale ,1859 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      Words by J. K.
    - The dews are sleeping on the grass: song & chorus San Francisco: Atwill & Co.,[1850s].Sacramento: R. Dale ,[1850s] (Box 17, Folder 7)
      Music by James R. Lawie
      Lithographer: Stackpole
    - When the swallows homeward fly San Francisco: W. H. Oakes,[1854] (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - The dying Californian, or, the brother's request: ballad Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1855.Cincinnati: D. A. Traux ,1855 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      Music by A. L. Lee
      Poetry by New England Diadem
      Also published by H. D. Hewitt, New Orleans; S. T. Gordon, New York; J. E. Gould, Philadelphia; and C. C. Clapp & Co., Boston.
    - He died in California Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1853.Cincinnati: D. A. Traux ,1855 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      Composed by I. B. Woodbury
      Also published by T. T. Barker, Boston; T. S. Berry, New York; J. E. Gould, Philadelphia; and C. C. Clapp & Co., Boston.
    - The returned Californian Boston: E. H. Wade,1852 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      Written by James Pierpont, Esq.
      Performed by S. C. Howard of Ordway's Aeolians
    - Highland polka: the only correct edition for dancing San Francisco: Salvator Rosa,[1858 -1860] (Box 17, Folder 8)
      Performed by C. Andres' Band
    - I'll think of thee, love San Francisco: Rasche & Sons,[1856 -1860].San Jose: A. Waldteufel ,[1856 -1860] (Box 17, Folder 9)
      Music by F. Rasche
      Poetry by Park Benjamin
    - He fell at his post doing duty San Francisco: W. H. Oakes,1856.Sacramento: Dougliss & Dale ,1856 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      Composed by R. Herold
      Words by Canton
    - San Francisco polka Baltimore: Geo. Willig,n.d.New Orleans: H. D. Hewitt ,[1852 -1856] (Box 17, Folder 9)
      Composed by A. Wallerstein
      Lithographer: A. Hoen & Co., Baltimore
    - The storm polka Baltimore: Geo. Willig,n.d.New Orleans: H. D. Hewitt ,[1852 -1856] (Box 17, Folder 9)
      Also published by W. C. Peters & Sons, Cincinnati.
    - The Golden Gate schottisch San Francisco: Salvator Rosa,1859 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      Composed by L. Stateler
    - Millie of the vale: ballad San Francisco: A. Kohler,1859.Sacramento: R. Dale ,1859 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Fleur de Marie (heroine of the mysteries of Paris): grand polka militaire San Francisco: A. Kohler,1859.Sacramento: R. Dale ,1859 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      Composed by W. McKorkell
    - California quadrille no. 1 San Francisco New York: S. C. Jollie,1853 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      Music by Jullien
    - The rose: varsoviana, as taught at Mr. Hazard's dancing academy San Francisco: Atwill & Co.,1856 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      From :Flowers of California
    - The pansy: schottische San Francisco: Atwill & Co.,1856 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Les fluxias: schotisch s.l.: s.d.,n.d. (Box 17, Folder 11)
      Music by Emile Perier
    - Forget me not: waltz San Francisco: Atwill & Co.,1856 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Rosy Hannah: ballad San Francisco: A. Kohler,1859.Sacramento: R. Dale ,1859 (Box 17, Folder 11)
      Melody by Henry Philips
      Symphonies and Accompaniments by W. McKorkell
      Performed by Miss Georgia Hodson, contralto of the New Orleans English Opera Troupe
  - Subseries b. 1860 - 1869
    - Trebelli Célèbre Polka Mazurka, op. 31 San Francisco: Matthias Gray,[1862 -1863] (Box 18, Folder 1)
      Music by Henri Roubier
      From :New and Fashionable Dance Music by Celebrated Composers
    - The Delta Phi Polka San Francisco: M. Gray,[1862 -1863] (Box 18, Folder 1)
      Music by A. S. Roe, Jr.
    - The Dude's March San Francisco: The Zeno Mauvais Music Company (Box 18, Folder 1)
      Music by J. F. Wagner
    - Valse Brilliante in A-flat San Francisco: M. Gray,[1869 -1870] (Box 18, Folder 1)
      Composed by Frédéric Chopin
    - Her bright smile haunts me still: a ballad San Francisco: M. Gray,[1869 -1870] (Box 18, Folder 1)
      Words by J. E. Carpenter
      From :English Songs for Voice and Piano
    - Chant du Berger San Francisco: Matthias Gray,[1867] (Box 18, Folder 2)
      Music by M. deColas
      From :Morceaux Favoris pour le Piano
    - The lonely watcher: a ballad San Francisco: Gray & Herwig,[1860].Sacramento: R. Dale, & Co. (Box 18, Folder 2)
      Words by Cha[rle]s Jefferys
      Lithographer: Drouaillet, Lithographers, San Francisco
    - Fair gallop San Francisco: Rosenberg's Music Store,[1860s] (Box 18, Folder 2)